{"tossups": [{"question": "The leader of this event had his followers march to the Sun Inn to demand the release of a group of prisoners. Participants in this event were pardoned by a president who described them as being \u201cas ignorant of our language as they were of our laws.\" A $2 million direct tax to fund the Quasi-War was an immediate cause of this event, during which a group of assessors from Quakertown was targeted. John Adams pardoned the leader of this event, which occurred five years after the similar Whiskey Rebellion. For ten points, what was this 1799 to 1800 farmers\u2019 rebellion in Pennsylvania?", "answer": "<b><u>Fries's</u></b> Rebellion (accept the <b><u>House Tax</u></b> Rebellion; accept the <b><u>Home Tax</u> </b>Rebellion; accept the <b><u>Heesses-Wasser</u></b> Uffschtand; prompt on answers denoting a \u201cRevolt of the Pennsylvania Dutch\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Two years prior to this battle, its victor defeated Murza Begich at the Vorzha River. A number of nobles from Ryazan were possibly killed at this battle, to which Oleg II was crucially late. The kingmaker Mamai led the losing side at this battle and was later killed by Tokhtamysh [[tohk-tah-MISH]]. The victor of this battle was given the epithet \u201cDonskoy\" in reference to a river near this battlefield. For ten points, what 1380 battle was a decisive victory for Dmitri, Prince of Moscow over the Golden Horde?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Kulikovo</u></b> (prompt on Battle of \u201cMamaev\u201d or Battle of the \u201cDon\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A governor of this region, named Abdullahi Sadiq [[SAH-deek]], attempted to influence one country to side with the Central Powers of World War One. That leader of this region was a member of the Harari people and forged an alliance with Mohammed Hassan of the Dervish State. A conference in Dire Dawa contributed to disputes over the name of this region, where a raid on an oil facility in Abole [[ah-BOH-leh]] led to a 2007 crackdown by Meles Zenawi\u2019s government. A 1970s war over this region began when Siad Barre\u2019s forces invaded it from the east. For ten points, name this region historically disputed between Somalia and Ethiopia.", "answer": "<b><u>Ogaden</u></b> (accept <b><u>Ogaadeen</u></b>; accept <b><u>Huwan</u></b>; accept <b><u>Soomaali Galbeed</u></b> prompt on \"Somali Region\" or \u201cWestern Somalia\u201d; prompt on \"Haud\" or \"Ethiopia\" or \"Abyssinia\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Person and body part required. This body part is described as being \u201cgaily frilled\u201d in a depiction that shows its owner next to a portrayal of a donkey. The owner of this body part was stationed at Naples prior to a battle in which it was hit by an arquebus shot. The loss of functionality in this body part was said to \u201cbring greater glory\u201d to its right counterpart following its injury at a 1571 victory for Don John of Austria and the Holy League. That injury led this body part's owner to be labelled the \u201cCripple of Lepanto.\u201d For ten points, name this body part belonging to the author of <em>Don Quixote</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Cervantes' Arm</u></b> (or Miguel de <b><u>Cervantes</u></b> Saavedra\u2019s left <b><u>arm</u></b>; accept equivalents; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This place's Dau Go cave contains remnants of sharp wooden columns used to sink Mongol ships. This place was the site of the raising of the flag of a provisional government led by Nguy\u1ec5n V\u0103n Xu\u00e2n [[WEHN VAHN ZHU-AHN]]. Legends state that the landscape of this area was formed when guardian dragons spat out jewels and jade to protect against invaders, and that Dragon King's seven-day marriage took place in this area's Thien Cung [[TYEN-KUNG]] cave. For ten points, containing over fifteen hundred limestone karst islands, name this arm of the Gulf of Tonkin that was, along with Haiphong Harbor, heavily mined by the U.S. Navy.", "answer": "<b><u>H\u1ea1 Long</u></b> Bay (or <b><u>Halong</u></b> Bay; or V\u1ecbnh <b><u>H\u1ea1 Long</u></b>; prompt on \u201cGulf of Tonkin\u201d prior to mention, do not accept or prompt on Haiphong Harbor)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "In one work, this man wrote of studying an \u201cin-between\u201d period of one figure\u2019s life after that figure\u2019s experiences in South Africa. That work by this author is subtitled <em>On the</em> <em>Origins of Militant Nonviolence</em>. A work by this author, originally planned as a chapter about \u201cemotional crises in late adolescence,\u201d tries to explain an exclamation given at a choir practice in Germany. For ten points, name this psychologist and author of <em>Gandhi\u2019s Truth</em> and <em>Young</em> <em>Man Luther</em> who is best known for coining the phrase \u201cidentity crisis.\u201d", "answer": "Erik <b><u>Erikson</u></b> (or Erik Homburger <b><u>Erikson</u></b>; accept Erik <b><u>Salomonsen</u></b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "An 1828 poem about one of these people focuses on his relationship with Maria and the revenge of her father, Kochubei. In a novel, one of these people falls in love with Aksinia, who is killed by a stray bullet. The lifestyles of these people in a valley by the title river are depicted in the novel <em>And Quiet Flows the Don</em>. A Tolstoy novel, published in <em>The Russian</em> <em>Messenger</em>, outlines the protagonist's relationship with one of these people named Eroshka who clashes with the Chechens. For ten points, name these people of the Ukrainian steppes, one of whom titles Lord Byron's <em>Mazeppa</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Cossack</u></b>s (accept Don <b><u>Cossack</u></b>; accept <b><u>Kozak</u></b>; prompt on \"Zaporizhian\" or \u201cUkrainian\u201d or \u201cRussian\u201d)", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "The Turner family competed with a company named for this early user of direct mail techniques. This man was inspired by a black material found in Italy to name a factory after the region of Etruria. Early in his career, John Flaxman originally worked under this man, who partnered with Thomas Whieldon. For three years, this man tried to replicate the blue and white Portland Vase. This producer of creamware created a medallion depicting a man in chains above the words \u201cAm I Not a Man and a Brother?\u201d For ten points, name this English abolitionist who industrialized pottery production.", "answer": "Josiah <b><u>Wedgwood</u></b> (accept <b><u>Wedgwood</u></b> pottery; accept Josiah <b><u>Wedgwood</u></b> and Sons Ltd.)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This book's author was present for a scene in this book, where she witnessed the pursuit of the <em>Goeben</em> and <em>Breslau</em> at age two. This book's author cited Thomas Mann, to depict the desires of Germany, in the section \"Flames of Louvain.\" Opening with the funeral of Edward VII [[the Seventh]], this book observes, \u201cOn history\u2019s clock it was sunset, and the sun of the old world was setting in a dying blaze of splendor never to be seen again.\u201d Consisting of the sections \u201cPlans,\u201d \u201cOutbreak,\u201d and \u201cBattle,\u201d for ten points, what Barbara Tuchman book detailed the events of the first month of World War One?", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Guns of August</u></b></em>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "Journalist Westbrook Pegler wrote an article which claimed this man must be reported to the \"Missing Person's Bureau\" after his RNC presidential nomination. This man's daughter, Nancy Kassebaum, was the first woman ever elected to a full term in the Senate without her husband having previously served in Congress. In one speech, this candidate claimed, \"The price of economic planning is the loss of economic freedom\" in reference to the continuation of FDR's New Deal programs. A landslide loss in the 1936 election was suffered by, for ten points, what Republican candidate and former governor of Kansas?", "answer": "Alf <b><u>Landon</u></b> (or Alfred Mossman <b><u>Landon</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "220 members of this ethnicity were killed in a disaster involving a ship departing from Cicero. A founder of the Chicago Bears, nicknamed \u201cPapa Bear,\u201d was a member of this ethnicity who was originally thought to have been among the dead on the aforementioned SS <em>Eastland</em>. A mayor of Chicago of this ethnicity was killed during a 1933 attempt on the life of FDR. Members of this ethnic group organized a large rally in Chicago Stadium as the Munich Crisis was unfolding. For ten points, Anton Cermak belonged to what ethnic group, many of whose members came from Bohemia?", "answer": "<b><u>Czech</u></b>-Americans (accept <b><u>Czech</u></b>oslovakians; accept natives of the <b><u>Czech</u></b> Republic or <b><u>Czechia</u></b>; accept <b><u>Bohemia</u></b>n Americans before \u201cBohemia\u201d is mentioned; prompt on \"Moravian\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Victor Gregg compared this event to being \u201ctrapped in a locked cage.\u201d After this event, one man compared the appearance of its central location to Dayton, Ohio and claimed, \u201cThere must be a ton of human bone meal in the ground.\u201d Arthur Harris claimed that the target of this event was \u201ca key transportation point.\u201d A mere six Lancasters were shot down during this event that targeted the \u201cFlorence of the Elbe.\u201d Kurt Vonnegut wrote about this event in <em>Slaughterhouse-Five</em>. For ten points, name this Allied aerial attack on a German town.", "answer": "<b><u>Bomb</u></b>ing of <b><u>Dresden</u></b> (or Fire<b><u>bomb</u></b>ing of <b><u>Dresden</u></b>; prompt on \u201cattack\u201d or similar answers in place of \u201cbombing\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This event led nearly 20,000 people in one nation\u2019s capital to protest and to call for the prime minister and his cabinet to resign for failing to prevent this event. Yasushi Nagao won the Pulitzer Prize in 1961 for photographing this event. The person who accomplished this event wrote with toothpaste on the walls of his jail cell, \u201cWould that I had seven lives to give for my country\u201d and \u201cLong live the Emperor\" before committing suicide. Perpetrated by 17-year-old Otoya Yamaguchi, for ten points, what event caused the death of the chairman of the Japan Socialist Party?", "answer": "<b><u>Assassination</u></b> of Inejir\u014d <b><u>Asanuma</u></b> (accept word forms of \"Assassination\"; accept descriptive answers like <b><u>Assassination</u></b> of the leader of the <b><u>Socialist</u></b>s in <b><u>Japan</u></b> or similar before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Despite being ethnically Azerbaijani, Mirza Davud Huseynov served the USSR as the first secretary of this present-day nation until his expulsion during the Great Purge. The nationalistic political faction known as the Rastokhez fueled Anti-Armenian riots in this nation put down by the military of Qahhor [[KAH-hohr]] Mahkamov. The title \"Founder Of Peace and National Unity, Leader of the Nation\" is used by this nation's authoritarian leader, Emomali Rahmon, who dominated its politics starting in the mid-1990s. The Dushanbe [[duhr-SHAHN-beh]] Riots occurred in, for ten points, which Central Asian nation?", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Tajikstan</u></b> (or <b><u>Tokjikiston</u></b>; or <b><u>Tadzhikistan</u></b>; or Jumhurii <b><u>Tojikiston</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In Jeremiah, a kingdom that shares its name with this person was \"called\" along with Ararat and Minni. John V [[the Fifth]] the Historian claimed that this man\u2019s namesake army was subjugated by a brother who founded the House of Togarmah. This eldest son of Gomer was first associated with a region of Scythia before lending his name to a \"kingdom\" that encompassed the Rhineland. A group named for this man traditionally lives to the east of the Iberian Sephardi community and often speaks Yiddish. For ten points, give this namesake of a group of German Jews.", "answer": "<b><u>Ashkenaz</u></b> (accept <b><u>Ashkenaz</u></b>i; accept <b><u>Ashkenaz</u></b>i Jews; accept <b><u>Ashkenaz</u></b>aic Jews; accept <b><u>Ashkenaz</u></b>im)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "The British referred to this vehicle as the Gannett Mark I and received over 1,200 of them via Lend-Lease. This craft's superiority in carrier landings made it a preferable choice compared to the Vought F4U Corvair. David McCampbell was an ace who registered all of his 34 kills in this vehicle. Many participants in the \u201cGreat Marianas Turkey Shoot\u201d used these fighters, which saw widespread use in 1943. Intended to counter the Mitsubishi Zero, this vehicle was billed as the \u201cbig brother\u201d of the Wildcat. For ten points, name this dominant U.S. fighter during the second half of the Pacific Theatre of World War Two.", "answer": "Grumman <b><u>F6F</u><u>Hellcat</u></b> (accept either underlined portion; prompt on \"Grumman\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A composer with this surname, who died of tuberculosis at 24, was the first female winner of the Prix de Rome for composition, for her cantata <em>Faust et Helene</em>. A musician with this surname reportedly memorized the entirety of Bach's <em>Well-Tempered Clavier</em> at just 10 years old. Aaron Copland wrote his <em>Symphony for Organ and Orchestra</em> for a music teacher with this surname who taught over 600 students at the American Conservatory in Fontainebleau. For ten points, give this surname of composer Lili and her sister, Nadia.", "answer": "<b><u>Boulanger</u></b> (accept Marie-Juliette Olga \"Lili\" <b><u>Boulanger</u></b>; accept Juliette Nadia <b><u>Boulanger</u></b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "The 154th episode of <em>Top Gear</em> focuses on the hosts' attempt to do this task. One man who attempted to complete this task, with the help of James Grant, died in what may have been a suicide the day before a scheduled debate about that attempt. Richard Burton was a rival of the aforementioned man, who claimed to have done this task shortly after Lake Tanganyika was discovered. John Hanning Speke claimed to have accomplished this task, which David Livingstone later attempted. For ten points, name this task of locating a place, the location of which is still debated today.", "answer": "Finding the <b><u>Source</u></b> of the <b><u>Nile</u></b> River (prompt on answers involving the confluence of the White and Blue Nile; accept equivalents in place of \u201cfinding\u201d; prompt on \"Nile\"; prompt on \u201cBlue Nile\u201d or \u201cWhite Nile\u201d or \u201cT\u2019ik\u2019uri Abayi\u201d or \u201can-Nil al-\u02beAzraqu\u201d or \u201can-nil al-'abyad\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Inspiring a figure in the <em>Canturbury Tales</em>, this man's knight, Nicholas Colfox, strangled former advisor Thomas of Woodstock. This monarch demolished Sheen Manor following the plague death of his wife, Anne of Bohemia. This ruler, whose reign began with a regency council led by John of Gaunt, was opposed by the \"Merciless Parliament,\" which aimed to halt this man's attempts to make peace during the One Hundred Years' War. A clash between the Yorks and the Lancasters was caused by the deposition of, for ten points, which 14th century Plantagenet king?", "answer": "<b><u>Richard II</u></b> (accept <b><u>Richard of Bordeaux</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>Clarence DeLaney was a co-founder of this company, one of whose earliest</u></b> <b><u>clients was Schlitz. Though not Google, employees of this company were referred to as</u></b> <b><u>\u201cAndroids\u201d of its founder. David Duncan was a partner at this organization who worked</u></b> <b><u>with a client that adopted the \u201cmark-to-market\u201d (+)</u> method of one practice. That client of this company was led by Jeffrey Skilling. Accenture branched off from this company, which was formerly a member of the Big Five along with Ernst and Young and Deloitte until it became (*) </b>embroiled in a 2001 scandal. For ten points, name this former accounting firm for Enron.", "answer": "<b><u>Arthur Andersen</u></b> LLP (accept <b><u>Andersen, Delaney and Company</u></b> before \"Duncan\" is mentioned; anti-prompt on \u201cAccenture\u201d plc; anti-prompt on \u201cAndersen Consulting\u201d)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>Roger of Torre Maggiore wrote a \u201cSorrowful Lament\u201d focusing on this military</u></b> <b><u>campaign, during which one side annihilated the crossbowmen under Count Simon. A</u></b> <b><u>preemptive bridge attack during this campaign was partly overseen by a Duke of</u></b> <b><u>Slavonia named Coloman. (+)</u> Gunpowder may have been employed during this campaign, in which Esztergom was besieged following the defeat of Bela IV. The Battle of Mohi was fought during this campaign, in which one side was led by (*) </b>Batu. For ten points, name this campaign in which a Central Asian empire expanded into Magyar territory.", "answer": "<b><u>Mongol</u></b>ic invasion of the Kingdom of <b><u>Hungary</u></b> (accept clear knowledge equivalents in place of \u201cinvasion\u201d; accept First or Second <b><u>Mongol</u></b> invasion of <b><u>Hungary</u></b>; prompt on \"Mongol invasion of Europe\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this conflict, the forces of Henri II Montmorency led a charge across a</u></b> <b><u>ditch at the Battle of Veillane. Ambrogio Spinola died of ill health during a siege in this</u></b> <b><u>war. The fortress of Casale was besieged twice during this conflict, in which Pinerolo,</u></b> <b><u>(+)</u> and other land taken by France, was renounced in the Treaty of Cherasco. A Piedmont Campaign was carried out during this war, which was precipitated by the deaths of Francesco IV and two other brothers of the House of (*) </b>Gonzaga. For ten points, name this war which was fought over the throne of a duchy in Italy.", "answer": "War of the <b><u>Mantuan Succession</u></b> (prompt on \"Thirty Years War\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man's refusal to join a financial house earned him the nickname \"The Lone</u></b> <b><u>Wolf of Wall Street.\" This man became the first chairman of the War Industries Board,</u></b> <b><u>which managed the United States's mobilization during World War One. At a meeting</u></b> <b><u>of the UN Atomic (+)</u> Energy Commission, this man presented a modified version of the Acheson\u2013Lilienthal Report which was rejected by the Soviet Union. This coiner of the term \"Cold (*) </b>War\" served as a close advisor to FDR on war supply. For ten points, name this financier whose namesake \"Plan\" was an effort to prevent the spread of nuclear weapons.", "answer": "Bernard <b><u>Baruch</u></b> (or Bernard Mannes <b><u>Baruch</u></b>; accept <b><u>Baruch</u></b> Plan)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Allen Walton founded a company in Hummelstown that was centered around</u></b> <b><u>this material. In the late 19th century, a popular variant of this material made</u></b> <b><u>Basswood Island in Wisconsin famous. The Clinton Hill and Park Slope (+)</u> Historic Districts are notable for the prevalence of this material. The ease with which it was carved led to the popularity of this material in the late-Victorian era in Brooklyn, (*) </b>Harlem, and on the Upper West Side of Manhattan. For ten points, townhouses across New York are known for their use of what Jurassic sandstone?", "answer": "<b><u>Brownstone</u></b> (accept Hummelstown <b><u>Brownstone</u></b>; accept Bass Island <b><u>Brownstone</u></b> Company)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>The largest church of this spiritual movement, Unity, was founded by Charles</u></b> <b><u>and Myrtle Filmore in 1889. Emma Curtis Hopkins, a leader in this spiritual movement,</u></b> <b><u>was referred to as the \u201cTeacher of Teachers.\u201d In his book,</u> </b><em><b><u>The Varieties of Religious</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Experience</u></b></em><b><u>, (+)</u> William James brands this spiritual philosophy as a \u201cMind-cure movement.\u201d The founder of Christian Science, Mary Baker Eddy, denied that she was inspired by her time as a student of the (*) </b>founder of this movement. For ten points, the foundations of what spiritual movement were laid by mesmerist Phineas P. Quimby?", "answer": "<b><u>New Thought</u></b> movement (or <b><u>Higher Thought</u></b>)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "<b><u>15th century historian Mustafa Ali justified this system by writing, \"War</u></b> <b><u>captives constituted as captured loot, and thus was allowed under</u> </b><em><b><u>sharia</u></b></em><b><u>.\" Ahmet III</u></b> <b><u>formally abolished this system following a series of insurrections from its</u></b> <b><u>beneficiaries. (+)</u> This system, from which Jewish and Roma people were exempt due to being \"Protected nations,\" was created by Murad I to counteract the influence of Turkish (*) </b>nobles with Western vassal-soldiers. The Ottomans utilized, for ten points, what method of child levies on Christian subjects to populate their Janissary Corps?", "answer": "<b><u>Devshirme</u></b> (accept <b><u>Dev\u015firme</u></b>; prompt on \"Child levy\" or \"Blood tax\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Plutarch pairs this historical figure with the orator and general Alcibiades [[al-</u><u>sih-BYE-ah-dees]] in his work,</u> </b><em><b><u>Parallel Lives</u></b></em><b><u>. The first speech given by this man was a</u></b> <b><u>wordless display of his battle scars to the Roman public. This man was put to death by</u></b> <b><u>his enemy-turned-ally-turned-enemy again, Attius (+)</u> Tullius, after this man's mother, Veturia, begged him not to sack his hometown. A (*) </b>Shakespearian tragedy is named for, for ten points, what semi-legendary hero of the Early Roman Republic who was exiled from Rome following his defeat of the Volsci [[VOHL-skee]]?", "answer": "Gnaeus Marcius <b><u>Coriolanus</u></b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>On this island, a free black carpenter used a book of images of Haitian leaders</u></b> <b><u>to inspire support for his failed slave uprising, the Aponte Revolt. This island\u2019s capital</u></b> <b><u>was occupied after a 1762 siege where British troops captured the Morro fort, which</u></b> <b><u>broke the (+)</u> asiento monopoly on this island\u2019s slave trade. This island\u2019s production of one cash crop boomed in response to the Haitian Revolution, from which many refugees fled across the Windward Passage to this island and settled around Baracoa, its first colonial settlement. (*) </b>Sugar planters led the Ten Years War for independence from Spain in, for ten points, what Caribbean island, whose capital is Havana?", "answer": "<b><u>Cuba</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Alejandro Lanusse contrasts this event with one on October 17, 1945 that</u></b> <b><u>involved \u201cthe masses imposing their will.\" Jorge Osinde hired a group of 300 men who</u></b> <b><u>took part in this event despite being tasked with defending a target of it. Hector</u></b> <b><u>Campora (+)</u> was present at this event, which occurred amid a gathering of over three million people witnessing the return of a leader from an (*) </b>eighteen-year exile in Spain. Taking place near a namesake airport, for ten points, what was this 1973 attack in which snipers fired into a crowd of Juan Per\u00f3n supporters in Buenos Aires?", "answer": "<b><u>Ezeiza</u></b> Massacre (accept attack at <b><u>Ezeiza</u></b> International Airport or clear-knowledge equivalents)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Lawyer Caleb Cushing was deployed to Qing China by this man to negotiate the</u></b> <b><u>Treaty of Wangxia, giving the U.S. a \"Most-favored Nation\" status. Due to intervention</u></b> <b><u>from Jefferson Davis, this man was the only president draped in the (+)</u> Confederate flag instead of the American flag during his funeral. A Democratic faction named for and founded by this man which ran on the sole platform of annexation of Texas dissolved following the nomination of dark horse candidate James K. Polk. \"His (*) </b>Accidency\" was the derisive nickname of, for ten points, which successor of William Henry Harrison?", "answer": "John <b><u>Tyler</u></b> (accept <b><u>Tyler</u></b> Party)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>Finno-Swedish officer Adam Laxman was one of the first people to circumvent</u></b> <b><u>this policy after returning a castaway to the Matsumae Family. This policy's strictest</u></b> <b><u>implementation came after Christian peasants</u> revolted in the (+) Shimabara Rebellion. Due in part to a yearly tribute to the </b><em><b>shogun</b></em><b>, the Dutch (*) </b>East India Company circumvented this policy by trading through the port of Dejima in modern Nagasaki. The Perry Expedition ended, for ten points, what period of Japanese self-isolation between the 17th and 19th century?", "answer": "<b><u>Sakoku</u></b> (accept <b><u>Locked Country</u></b>; accept <b><u>Japanese Isolation</u></b> before \"Japanese\"; prompt on \"Isolation\"; prompt on answers like \"Edo Period\" or \"Tokugawa Shogunate\" despite not being a policy)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}